James A. Dunn Papers 5878
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
James A. Dunn Papers
1967-1981
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Dunn, James A.
5878
11.56 cubic feet
10 linear ft.
Research proposals, reports.
Proposals and reports concerning occupational education.
5722891
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 12, 2004
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, April 22, 2014
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of 27 bound volumes of proposals, and 41 bound volumes of project products and reports originating during James Dunn's tenure at: Cornell Institute for Occupational Education, The American Institutes for Research and the University of Michigan Inter-Professional Research Center for Pupil Personnel Services. In addition there are 21 paperback bound volumes of Career Education materials developed as a comprehensive K-12, Career Education Curriculum for the U.S. Office of Education.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Vocational education.; Career education.; Occupational training.; Dunn, James A.
5722891
- SERIES I - RESEARCH PROPOSALS, 1968-1980 (Box 1)
  - PROPOSALS 1968-70, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    "A Procedure for Teacher Recognition of Children's Debilitating School Anxiety." "The Development and Validation of an Evaluation system for Ascertaining The Effectiveness of Educational Laboratories and Research and Development Centers." "A Proposal for the Evaluation of Teacher Training Activities Submitted to the Department of HEW."
  - PROPOSALS 1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    "Preparation of Twelve Reports on Provision of Instruction in Public Schools for Teaching Exceptional Children." "Research and Development of Advanced Instructional System Specifications." "A Study of the Feasibility of the Apprenticeship Work-Study Program for Multi-Site Tryout and Evaluation." "Experimental Schools Program." "The Design and Pilot Test of a Survey to Assess Existing Barriers to Participation of Women In Continuing Education." "An Assessment of Vocational Guidance Needs As Perceived by California Community College Students And An Evaluation of Available Guidance Materials And Systems in Terms of These Perceived Needs." "Proposal for Professional Services in the Evaluation of the RTF Developmental Resting Program." "Cost and Staff Qualifications Quotations for the Summative Evaluation of a Comprehended Staff Qualifications Quotations for the Summative Evaluation of a Comprehensive Career Education Model." "Final Development and Field Testing of a Program for Training Educational Research and Development Personnel." "An Evaluation of the Training Provided to WIN Clients."
  - PROPOSALS 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    "An Evaluation of the Hayward Manpower Services Delivery System Concept." "Design and Testing of a Model Curriculum for Consumer and Home Economics Teacher Preservice Education." "Individualized Introductory Psychology Course Pilot Project." "Career Education Curriculum Development: Awareness, Orientation, and Exploration." "Study of the Utilization of Recipients of Allied Health Advanced Traineeships." "Information System for Educational Research and Development Training Programs." "The Creation and Operation of a Center for Resource Development in Adult Education." "Development of a Critical Incident Based Rationale for Individualizing Introductory Psychology Courses."
  - PROPOSALS 1973 VOL. I (Box 1, Folder 4)
    "Assessing the Feasibility of a Needs-Based Curriculum and Instructional Model for Higher Education." "Prospectus for the Design and Development of Career Education Training Programs for Educational Personnel." "Assessing the Feasibility of a Needs-Based Model for Curriculum and Instruction in Post-Secondary Education." "A Study of Alternative Models for Career Guidance." "ERIC Clearinghouse on Career Education."
  - PROPOSALS 1973 VOL. II (Box 1, Folder 5)
    "Development of a Model of ROTC/Army Officer Career Commitment." "Letter Proposal: Comparative EBCE Cost Analysis and Fiscal Accounting Project." "Proposal for the Evaluation of Primary Education Centers."
  - PROPOSALS 1974 VOL. I (Box 1, Folder 6)
    "Psychological Carrying Capacity of Recreational Areas." "Population Policy Research Proposal - The Antecedents and Consequents of High Level Migration from the Philippines to the U.S." "Development of Curriculum Materials Relative To Small Business Ownership and Management Training for Grades 10-12." "Career Awareness and Exploration for Spanish-Speaking Migrant Children, K-6."
  - PROPOSALS 1974 VOL. II (Box 2, Folder 1)
    "Vocational Education Curriculum Specialist Program." "Curriculum Development in Home Economic-Related Occupational Areas." "Research on the Regulation of Fertility - Antecedents and Consequences of the Motivation for Fertility Control: A Cross-Cultural Study."
  - PROPOSALS 1974 VOL. III (Box 2, Folder 2)
    "A Study of Career Education Implementation in Six School Districts." "Field Test and Revision of 88 Career Education Curriculum Units." "Proposal for the Design and Development of SRA Career Learning Center System."
  - PROPOSALS 1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    "Overcoming Barriers To Mainstreaming: A Problem-Solving Approach." "Vocational Training and Placement of the Severely Handicapped." "An Assessment of the Centers Programs Supported Under the Education of the Handicapped Act." "Evaluation of Special Programs for Children with Specific Learning Disabilities."
  - PROPOSALS 1976 VOL. I (Box 2, Folder 4)
    "TV-CAP: Career Awareness Programs For Children."
  - PROPOSALS 1976 VOL. II (Box 2, Folder 5)
    "Overcoming Barriers To Mainstreaming: A Problem-Solving Approach." "Vocational Training and Placement of the Severely Handicapped." "Curriculum Workshops For Leaders in Vocational Education." "Workshops to Promote Women's Educational Equity." "Development of Curricula for Vocational Preparation of Gifted and Talented Students in Secondary and Post Secondary Education."
  - PROPOSALS 1976 VOL. III (Box 2, Folder 6)
    "Business, Labor, Industry, and Schools: A Demonstration Project." "Demonstrating Career Education in the Community College."
  - PROPOSALS 1976 VOL. IV (Box 2, Folder 7)
    "Special Mail Surveys of Sponsors of Work Incentive Program (WIN)." "Modules on Sexism in Education."
  - PROPOSALS 1976 VOL. V (Box 3, Folder 1)
    "Evaluation of the State Capacity Building Program in Dissemination." "Exploring the Feasibility of Providing In-Service Training Through the Vehicle of a Home Study Correspondence Course."
  - PROPOSALS 1977 VOL. I (Box 3, Folder 2)
    "Cornell Institute for Research and Development in Occupational and Continuing Education." "ISSOE Dissemination Planning - Phase I" "Instructional Support System Occupational Education." "The Identification of Factors Associated With Sex-Role Stereotyping in Occupational Education." "Special Projects and Adult Education Personnel Training Projects." "Optimum Utilization and Cost Effectiveness of Resources in Occupational Education." "Needs Assessment of Small Businessmen in Applied Business Techniques." "The Impact of Developmental Studies with Occupational Education Two-Year College Students." "Occupational Education Staff Development Services." "A Cooperative Intra-Institutional Process for Equity Actions." "Network to Access Continuing Education." "Problem Solving Skills in Adult Education."
  - PROPOSALS 1977 VOL. I (con't) (Box 3, Folder 3)
    "A Study of Manpower Needs in Agriculture/Agribusiness." "Conceptual Change and Cognitive Representation of Knowledge."
  - PROPOSALS 1977 VOL. II (Box 3, Folder 4)
    "An Evaluation Model for Educational Programs Serving the Severely Handicapped." "Mainstreaming Workshops for Vocational Administrators." "Identification of Evaluated, Exemplary Activities in Career Education (K-12)."
  - PROPOSALS 1978 VOL. I (Box 3, Folder 5)
    "Field Testing Vocational Education Curriculum Specialists Materials. (technical and business proposals)"
  - PROPOSALS 1978 VOL. II (Box 3, Folder 6)
    "Community Resource Materials: A Sharing System for New York State Continuing Education Programs." "Re-Entry Women: A Prototype Model to Overcome Career Stereotyping." "A Dissemination/Resource Sharing Network for Faculty-Developed Instructional Material." "Delivery Feasibility and Effectiveness of Modularized Instruction in Land Treatment of Waste." "Research Support Grant for Research and Development Center." "Materials for Evaluation of Occupational Education Programs." "Program to Develop Career-Choice and Decision-Making Skills." "Problems and Promises: A Descriptive Assessment of Two-Year College Co-Op Education Programs."
  - PROPOSALS 1978 VOL. III (Box 3, Folder 7)
    "Matrix to Cross-Reference DOT USOE - Census Codes." "Modular Learning Units in Energy Conservation for Two-Year College Occupational Programs." "Spotlight on Exemplary Research and Development Projects." "Improving Local Programming for Minority Business Enterprise." "OUR's - Phase III: Facilitating Factors in Resources Exchange." "Occupational Education Staff Development for Two-Year Colleges." "Identification of Factors Associated with Sex-Role Stereotyping in Occupational Education: Phase II." "Assessment of Learning Needs of New York City Adults."
  - PROPOSALS 1978 VOL. IV (Box 3, Folder 8)
    "Beyond Employment: Study of Expectations for Secondary Occupational Education." "Leadership Training Program for Career Education Supervisors." "Leadership Development Programs for Experienced, Mid-Career Vocational Educators." "Study of Non-Formal Learning Opportunities for Adults."
  - PROPOSALS 1978 VOL. V (Box 4, Folder 1)
    "ISSOE Dissemination - Phase II." "ISSOE - Student Guidance and Development of Personalized Occupational Education Programs." "Instructional Support System Occupational Education - IV." "Field Testing Student Reporting System - ISSOE Phase IV." "ISSOE Articulation - Secondary, Post-Secondary, Adult and CETA - ISSOE Phase IV."
  - PROPOSALS 1979 VOL. I (Box 4, Folder 2)
    "Basic Skill Development Through Vocational Education."
  - PROPOSALS 1979 VOL. II (Box 4, Folder 3)
    "Adult Learning in Non-School Settings."
  - PROPOSALS 1979 VOL. III (Box 4, Folder 4)
    "Basic Research Support Grant." "CIOE/AVEA Social Impact of Occupational Education." "Two-Year Community College Staff Development." "Development/Testing of Methods to Overcome Sex-role Stereotyping in Enrollments." "Factors Associated with Sex-role Stereotyping in Health Occupations Education and Technical Education." "ISSOE Dissemination - Phase III." "ISSOE Instructional Planning." "Expansion of Student Reporting System - Phase V." "Extending the Benefits of Cooperative Education Programs in New York State Two-Year College." "Staff Development Materials for Vocational Educators of Adults."
  - PROPOSALS 1979 VOL. IV (Box 4, Folder 5)
    "Collection, Analysis and Dissemination of Employment Demand Data for Agriculture/Agribusiness in New York State."
  - PROPOSALS 1980 VOL. I (Box 4, Folder 6)
    "Cornell Institute for Occupational Education." "Basic Skills, Life Skills and Affective Learning in ISSOe." "Administrator Management of ISSOe Programs - Program Design." "Accelerating Student Progress through ISSOE: Optional Programming for Gifted Students." "Non-technical Outcomes of Vocational Education: Statewide Assessment." "Readability of Vocational Texts." "Expansion and Testing of Staff Development Materials for Vocational Educators of Adults." "Planning and Projecting Long-Range Curriculum Needs for Post-Secondary Vocational Education in New York State." "Technical Assistance for In-Depth Analysis of Data from LEA Occupational Education Program Assessments." "Use of Specialized Equipment in Educating for Occupations." "A Study to Examine the Extent and Quality of Services Provided by Post-Secondary Institutions to Persons with Handicapping Conditions Enrolled in Occupational Education Programs."
  - PROPOSALS 1980 VOL. II (Box 4, Folder 7)
    "Dissemination and Implementation of the Cooperative Education Guidelines for Program Development at Two-Year Colleges in New York State." "Energy-Related Manpower Needs Projection." "Managing Student Progress: ISSOE Student Planning and Reporting System Field-Test - Phase II." "Employment Demand Data for Agriculture/Agribusiness in New York State." "New York State Continuing Education Needs Assessment Analysis." "Adult Basic Education Programs in New York State." "Teaching Basic Competencies Through Home Economics Education." "Inservice Education for Agriculture Teachers." "Alcohol and Drug-Related Problems of Vocational Adjustment of Occupational vs. Non-Occupational Students." "Meaningful Learning Styles: Their Role in Science and Mathematics Participation."
  - PROPOSALS 1980 VOL. III (Box 4, Folder 8)
    "Alcohol and Drug-related Problems of Vocational Adjustment of Occupational vs. Non- Occupational Students." "Cornell Institute for Occupational Education." "Basic Skills, Life Skills and Affective Learning in ISSOE." "Administrator Management of ISSOE Programs - Program Design." "Accelerating Student Progress Through ISSOE: Optional Programming for Gifted Students." "Social Outcomes of Vocational Education: Statewide Assessment." "Readability of Vocational Texts." "Expansion and Testing of Staff Development Materials for Vocational Educators of Adults." "Planning and Projecting Long-Range Curriculum Needs for Post-Secondary Vocational Education in New York State." "Technical Assistance for In-depth Analysis of Data from LEA Occupational Education Program Assessing." "Use of Specialized Equipment in Educating for Occupations." "A Study to Examine the Extent and Quality of Services Provided by Post-Secondary Institutions to Persons with Handicapping Conditions Enrolled in Occupational Education Programs." "Dissemination and Implementation of the Cooperative Education Guidelines for Program Development at Two-Year Colleges in New York State." "Energy-related Manpower Needs Projection." "Managing Student Progress: ISSOE Student Planning and Reporting System Field-Test - Phase II." "Employment Demand Data for Agriculture/Agribusiness in New York State." "A Project to Establish a Regional Development Network in Response to the New York State Continuing Education Needs Assessment Analysis." "A Project to Establish a Data Collection and Analysis System for Adult Basic Education Programs in New York State."
- SERIES II - RESEARCH REPORTS (Box 5)
  - "Professional Characteristics and Functions of Selected Midwestern Pupil Personnel Workers.", 1967 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - "A Study of School Classroom Behavior from Diverse Evaluative Frameworks: Developmental, Mental Health, Substantive Learning, Group Process.", 1967 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - "Midwest Research Center for Pupil Personnel Service: Summary Status Report, Part I - Research and Service Activities.", 1967 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    includes: "Psychological Processes and Pupil Personnel Services."
  - "School Anxiety and Cognitive Functioning: Exploratory Studies.", 1967 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - "Training and Certification of Midwestern Pupil Personnel workers.", 1967 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - "Project Plan Development, Part I.", 1967-1970 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - "Project Plan Development, Part II.", 1967-1970 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - "NUEA ABE Summer Institutes: Evaluation and Documentation.", 1968 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - "POS Specifications and Related Transformation Tables.", 1970 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - "Student-Parent Long Range Goal formulation Program.", 1970 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - "PLAN Master Objectives.", 1970 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - "Development of an Apprenticeship Work-Study Program Model for the Cross-Training of Physical Scientists for Work in Educational Research and Development.", 1971 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Includes: "Procedures for Conducting An Apprenticeship Work-Study Program."
  - "AIR - Results of the Pilot Test of the NCERD/OPPE Products Evaluation System.", 1972 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Volume I
  - "AIR - Knowledge Products, Part I - from the Regional Educational Laboratories and Research and Development Centers.", 1972 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Volume II
  - "The AIR Career Guidance Program - Thinking About Your Future. A-H.", 1973 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - "The AIR Career Guidance Program - Finding Out About Yourself. I-O.", 1973 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - "AIR - Establishing Development Objectives.", 1973 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - "Resource Book of Sample Lesson Units for Career Education: Residual Modules.", 1974 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - "Source Book of Teacher Developed Instructional Units.", 1974 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - "Career Education Curriculum Development: Grades K-9.", 1974 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - "Career Education: Sample Instructional Materials.", 1974 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - "Resource Book of Sample Lesson Units For Career Education.", 1974 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - "Teacher's Guide To Career Education: Primary Grades.", 1974 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - "Instructional Systems Options and Guidelines for the Dissemination and Implementation of Career Education.", 1974 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - "Procedures of the National Advisory Panel.", 1974 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - "VECES: Vocational Education Curriculum Specialist Project.", 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Vol. I-IV and Final Report; Includes: Instructor/Administrator Guide; Study Guide - Teaching/Learning Modules; Final Report on VECES.
  - "Vocational Education: Instructional Systems Theory.", 1976 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - "Vocational Education: Introductory Material.", 1976 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - "CCEM: Career Curriculum Education Materials.", 1976 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - "CCEM: Career Curriculum Education Materials Modules.", 1976 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - "CCEM: Field Test Report of 130 Career Education Modules.", 1976 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - "CIOE Annual Reports, Vol. I.", 1971-1978 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - CIOE: A Review of the Change Literature with Implications for ISSOE Dissemination.", 1978-1981 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - "ISSOE: Managing Student Progress, Systems Overview.", 1980 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - "CIOE (Cornell Institute for Occupational Education): Teaching Basic Skills Through Vocational Educational, Technical Report - Literature Search.", 1980 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - "CIOE: Teaching Basic Skills Through Vocational Education, Technical Report - Readability Analyses of Selected Vocational Texts.", 1980 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - "CIOE: Teaching Basic Skills Through Vocational Education - Teacher's Guide.", 1980 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- SERIES III: CAREER EDUCATION MATERIALS (Box 10)
  - "Field Test Report: 130 Career Education Modules, Part I-IV.", 1976 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Vol. I-IV
  - "Goal Formulation and Personal Planning.", 1977 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    Vol. I-V
  - "Learning About Self.", 1977 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - "Learning About The World of Work.", 1977 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - "Publisher Procurement For Educational Products.", 1977 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - "Toward More Natural Field Testing of Classroom Materials.", 1977 (Box 10, Folder 6)